Julia Harwood Caverno Papers, 1885-1949
Smith College Archives
Julia Harwood Caverno Papers
1885-1949
Caverno, Julia Harwood.
RG 42
1 box (.45 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The materials document the life and career of Julia Harwood Caverno, as a member of the Greek Department.
Biographical Note
Julia Harwood Caverno was born to Rev. Charles and Anna Watson Caverno on December 19, 1862 in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. She received both her B.A. and M.A. degrees from Smith College in 1887 and 1890 respectively. While she was working on her M.A., Caverno taught Greek and Latin at the Grant Collegiate Institute in Chicago (1887-1893).
In 1893 Caverno came to Smith College as an instructor in Greek. She was soon promoted to a full professor. Between 1912 and her retirement in 1931, she served as the head of the department. Upon her retirement, Caverno's past students showed their respect for her by establishing the Julia Harwood Caverno Prize, which is awarded annually to a student for excellence in Greek. Julia Harwood Caverno died on February 2, 1949.
The Caverno Room in Smith College's Neilson Library is named in her honor.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Julia Harwood Caverno Papers contain biographical materials, correspondence, photographs, publications, speeches, lecture notes, student recommendations, part of her work for her Master's thesis and her scrapbook.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Additional Information
Related Material
80. Class of 1887 Records
- Biographical Materials 1887-1949, n.d. (Box 696, Folder 1)
- Correspondence 1893-1943, n.d. (Box 696, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, Grierson 1901-41, n. d. (Box 696, Folder 3)
- Photographs 1887, n. d. (Box 696, Folder 4)
- Publication: The Figures of Homer 1892 (Box 696, Folder 5)
- Publication: "The Messenger in Greek Tragedy" 1917 (Box 696, Folder 6)
- Publication: "So Big" n.d. (Box 696, Folder 7)
- Publication: "How Can the Colleges and High Schools cooperate to stimulate an interest in the study of Greek?" 1908 (Box 696, Folder 8)
- Lecture Notes n.d. (Box 696, Folder 9)
- Speeches 1915-39 (Box 696, Folder 10)
- Student Recommendations 1904-21 (Box 696, Folder 11)
- Master's Thesis 1889-90 (Box 696, Folder 12)
- Retirement 1931 (Box 696, Folder 13)
- Scrapbook 1885-1943 (Box 696, Folder 14)